Min Shi

Dallas, TX | (469) 403-7557 | minmiashi@gmail.com | LinkedIn Link | GitHub Page

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Experienced data analyst with 4 years of diverse dataset expertise. Skilled in data programming and analysis for macro and micro questions, as well as real-world problems. Trilingual and eager to learn. Seeking 2024 internship to apply data analytics skills.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Dallas

December 2024

Ph.D., Political Science

GPA 3.942

M.S., Social Data Analytics and Research (STEM)

GPA 3.942

M.S., Business Analytics (STEM) – Data Science Track

GPA 4.0

Graduate Teaching / Research Assistantship; John Forrest Kain Scholarship; Government and Political Science Scholarship

WORK EXPERIENCE

School of Economic, Political & Policy Sciences at UTD, Richardson, TX

Research Assistant

May 2020 – Present

- Lead survey and web data collection, perform data cleaning, model building, statistical analytics, causal reference and compose reports for diverse collaborative research papers spanning global health, political economy, and public policy
- Manage and guide undergraduate research assistants, fostering independent work, seamless collaboration, and timely project delivery. Deliver speeches on quantitative analytics, research methodologies, and report writing

Lucion Technology Corp., Ltd., China

Database Management Intern

une 2017 – August 2017

- Collaborated with IT department manager to manage enterprise users' information, orders of services, billing, and the deployed network devices data using MySQL, resulting in a 40% improvement in data extraction efficiency
- Visualized network structures of Lucion Tech. Corp. in Microsoft Visio
- Created weekly business analytics reports based on users' structure analysis and competitor research

Jinan Wangjia Education & Technology Corp., Ltd., China

Data Analyst

March 2016 – May 2017

- Designed questionnaires for assessments of more than 20 courses & teachers, created business intelligence reports for course & staff management, and improved satisfaction rate by 30%
- Upgraded staff & students' information management using the Microsoft Access database system

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Analysis of the Effect of COVID-19 on US Trade and US Firms, UT Dallas

May 2023 – July 2023

- Synthesized data via Python and created fixed-effect regression models to identify correlations and causal mechanisms
- Developed and Implemented machine learning and deep learning models to conduct counterfactual analysis
- Presented findings at the 2023 Applied Data Science International Conference

Extensive Analysis of Table Spreads Industry (Conagra Brands' Project), UT Dallas

February 2023 - May 2023

- Researched over 1.3 million records to identify key metrics contributing to the sales of top brands
- Evaluated strengths and weakness of Conagra Brands compared to competitors in each sub-category
- Built fixed-effect models and time series models in SAS to predict future directions for Conagra Brands

Geospatial Truck Fleet Big Data Analytics and Visualization, UT Dallas

August 2022 – November 2022

- Processed geospatial data ingestion, transformation, and database creation using the Hadoop ecosystem
- Explored and visualized data in Tableau by connecting to Hadoop ecosystem server
- Conducted modeling to analyze factors affecting truck driver risk and provided recommendations

Payroll Management System Database Design via MySQL, UT Dallas

June 2022 - August 2022

- Led a group of five in designing a MySQL-based payroll management database consisting of 13 tables
- Improved efficiency in ETL processes and payroll database management through the implementation of stored functions, procedures, and triggers

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Programming & Tools: Python, R, SQL, SAS, Stata, Tableau, Power BI, Alteryx, Appian, UiPath, ACCELQ, Microsoft Office Database & Big Data: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mango DB, Amazon RDS, Hadoop, Sqoop, Hive, Impala, Pig, Spark Certificates: Graduate Certificate in Applied Machine Learning at UTD, AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Google Analytics,

Alteryx Designer Core Certificate, Appian Certified Associate Developer, ACCELQ Automation Engineer

Languages: English, Chinese, Japanese